Guide to the Terry Allen Winograd Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Terry Allen Winograd papers
1963-2006
SC1165
Winograd, Terry.
38 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Terry Allen Winograd (1946-), an impressive scholar and professor of computer science at Stanford University, is known for his research on artificial intelligence and natural language. As a PhD student at MIT from 1968-1970, Winograd wrote SHRDLU, a computer program for understanding natural language.
During Winograd’s successful career at Stanford University he co-directed the Stanford Human-Computer Interaction Group and advised a PhD student in the mid-1990s named Larry Page, who later co-founded Google. In addition to his work in Stanford’s Computer Science Department, Winograd also helped found the Hasso Plattner Institute of Design.
Scope and Contents
Terry Allen Winograd papers include 33 boxes of print and audiovisual files dating back to the 1960s from Winograd’s own education and his career as a professor at Stanford University. The collection includes professional files, publications, research files, teaching files, audiovisual materials, computer files, and subject files on individual students.
Access Terms
Computer science--Research; Computer science--Study and teaching; Computer science.; Computer scientists--California.; Computer user interface; Computers--Technological innovations.
Collection Contents
- Professional files
  - Cuba (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Online Comm (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - UNL Permission (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - UCC (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - UCC (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - World Center (1 of 2) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - World Center (2 of 2) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - World Center (1 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - World Center (2 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - World Center (3 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - LACP Random (1 of 2) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - LACP Random (2 of 2) (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Winograd's Papers (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Newell, Allen (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Sespa (1 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Sespa (2 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Publications (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - NSF 80 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Software design book (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Workshop Maps (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Workshop Book (1 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Workshop Book (2 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Papert, Seymour (1 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Papert, Seymour (2 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Institute of Design, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pygmalion, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Design95, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Publications
  - Interrupt; Science for the People; Spark (Box 20)
  - Science for the People; The CPSR Newsletter (Box 21)
  - Winograd College Papers, 1963-1970 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1965 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1966 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1967 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1968 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1969 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 1970 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1971 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1972 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 1973 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 1974 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 1975 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 1976 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - 1977 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - 1978 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - 1979 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - 1980 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - 1983 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - 1984 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - 1985 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - 1986 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - 1987 (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 1987 (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 1988 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1989 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 1990 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 1991 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 1992-1994 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - 1995-1999 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Research files
  - CPSR (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - ?? (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Military Funding CS (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Military Funding - MIT (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Military Funding - Stanford (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Military Funding - Various Articles (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Conference: Ethical Issues Associated w/Science Research for the Military (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Computers/CPSR and SDI (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - SDI Boycott Updates (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - SDI Pledge at Stanford (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Open Letter to Congress (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - UCS (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - SDIO and various opposition (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Mailings/CPSR (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - History/CPSR (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - CPSR Email (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - The Journal of Community Communications, 1979-1982 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - The CPSR Newsletter @ Pantry Cabinet (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - SDI Articles (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - CPSR - Miscellaneous (1 of 2) (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - CPSR - Miscellaneous (2 of 2) (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Military/General (1 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Military/General (2 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Military/General (3 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - MIT (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - CPP (1 of 2) (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - CPP (2 of 2) (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - ALEPH (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - ASD (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - CPSR (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - DL Slides (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - HCI Center (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - HUB (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - IDM (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Interval (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Mobile Media (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Proposals (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Proposals (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - AI (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - CS147 (1 of 2) (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - CS147 (2 of 2) (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - AI Reprints & Reports (1 of 3) (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - AI Reprints & Reports (2 of 3) (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - AI Reprints & Reports (3 of 3) (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - ATI (1 of 3) (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - ATI (2 of 3) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - ATI (3 of 3) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Goffman (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Lighthill (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Speech (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - AI Reports (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Interval - Lee (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Infoknitter (1 of 2) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Infoknitter (2 of 2) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Cambridge (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Xerox (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Fifth Generation (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Reports (Box 27)
  - Language Reports (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Harvey A. Cohen (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Smalltalk 76 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - IBM: Pictureworld: A Concept for Future Office System, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Bruce Buchanan (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Science Against the People, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Other (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Bamberger, Jeanne (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Pask, Gordon (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Reprints (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Reprints - LISP, etc. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Logo (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - McDermott, Drew V. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - No Business as Usual (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Outer Space (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - MIT/AI (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - MIT/AI (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 31)
  - Military Funding of Research, Technical Reports on AI, Miscellaneous publications (Box 33)
- Teaching files
  - Courses
    - CS 47N (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - CS 201 (1 of ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - CS 201 (2 of ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - CS 201 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - CS 201 Handouts (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Computers and Society (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - CS 247 (1 of 2), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - CS 247 (2 of 2), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - CS 247a (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - CS 247a (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - CS 247a (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - CS 247a (4 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - CS 247b (1 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - CS 247b (2 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - CS 247b (3 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - CS 247b (4 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - CS 247b (5 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - CS/LING 265, 1974/1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - CS/LING 266 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - CS/LING 276 (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - CS/LING 276 (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - CS/LING 276 (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - CS/LING 276 (4 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - AI Courses (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - AI Courses (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - CS 276 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - CS 276 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - CS 276 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - CS 277 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - CS 365 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Misc. Readings (1 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Misc. Readings (2 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Readings (3 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Misc. Readings (4 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Misc. Readings (5 of ) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Misc. Readings (6 of ) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Misc. Readings (7 of ) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Misc. Readings (8 of ) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - CS 377 (1 of 3), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - CS 377 (2 of 3), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - CS 377 (3 of 3), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - CS 378 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - CS 378 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - CS 378 Readings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - CS 378 Readings, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - CS 447b (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - CS 447b (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - CS 378 (1 of 2), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - CS 378 (2 of 2), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - CS 378, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - CS 378 Original (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - CS 378 Original (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - CS 447 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - CS 447 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - CS 247b (Box 3)
    - CS 378 Course Readings, 1996 (Box 3)
    - CS 201 Reader, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Computing and Social Responsibility: A Collection of Course Syllabi, 1990 (Box 3)
    - CS 147 (1 of 3), 1993/1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - CS 147 (2 of 3), 1993/1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - CS 147 (3 of 3), 1993/1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - CS 247 Handouts (1 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - CS 247 Handouts (2 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - CS 247 Handouts (3 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - CS 247 Handouts (4 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - CS 378 (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - CS 378 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - CS 378 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - CS147 (1 of 2) (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - CS147 (2 of 2) (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - HCI: CS147 Homework Asignments, 1999 Autumn (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - CS147, 2000 Fall (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - CS147, 2002 Fall (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - CS147 Articles (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - CS147 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Theses (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Uzureau, Erik F. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Transparencies: Xerox Star User Interface (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Gips, Jonathan Peter (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Winograd (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Student idea logs
    - Rob Bence (Box 34)
    - April Alexander (Box 34)
    - Jonathan Bailey (Box 34)
    - Jason C. Bautista (Box 34)
    - David Black (Box 34)
    - Hayden Bursk (Box 34)
    - Timothy Caclems (Box 34)
    - Anuraag Chigurupati (Box 34)
    - Jaki Clark (Box 34)
    - Paul Doersch (Box 34)
    - Garret Bastham (Box 34)
    - Evershed, Gervais, Merrill, Schroeder (Box 34)
    - Julie Finkelstein (Box 34)
    - Michael Fisher (Box 34)
    - Michael Fisher (Box 34)
    - Andrew Gadson (Box 34)
    - Siddharth Gopalan (Box 34)
    - Matt Jones (Box 35)
    - Po Kai (Box 35)
    - Chetan Kalyan (Box 35)
    - Isabelle Kim (Box 35)
    - Zhifeng Koh (Box 35)
    - Gordon Koo (Box 35)
    - John Kuera (Box 35)
    - Henry A. Lee (Box 35)
    - Christopher Lin (Box 35)
    - Stephen Lindholm (Box 35)
    - Ariel Lin (Box 35)
    - Sarah Louise Martin (Box 35)
    - Wesley Mateo (Box 35)
    - Kelly Mayes (Box 35)
    - Andrew L. Meyer (Box 35)
    - Michael Morgan (Box 35)
    - David Murray (Box 35)
    - Nate (Box 35)
    - Matt Paden (Box 35)
    - Joyce Pan (Box 35)
    - Steven Peng (Box 35)
    - Luiz Pereira (Box 35)
    - Jessica Richman (Box 36)
    - Jason Robinson (Box 36)
    - Andy Russell (Box 36)
    - Jeff Seibert (Box 36)
    - Prowpannarai Mallikamarl Tongliemnak (Box 36)
    - Thai Tran (Box 36)
    - Timothy Vy (Idea Log 1) (Box 36)
    - Timothy Vy (Idea Log 2) (Box 36)
    - Yan Yan (Box 36)
    - Yin Yin Wu (Box 36)
    - Nesra Yannier (Box 36)
    - Andrew Yen (Box 36)
    - Jessica Yuan (Box 36)
    - 2010 Project Critiques (Box 36)
    - Final Project Fair Grading Sheets (Box 36)
- Audiovisual materials
  - CHI 92 Video Program: Striking A Balance, 1992; 0 (Box 10)
  - CHI 97 Video Program: Looking to the Future, 1997; 0 (Box 10)
  - CHI 99 Opening Plenary, 1999; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - CHI 99 Video Program: The CHI is the Limit, 1999; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - CHI 2001 Video Program: Anyone. Anywhere., 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - CHI 2002 Video Program: Changing the World, Changing Ourselves, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Computer Professionals and Social Responsibility Part 2, 1988; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - CPSR Camera A Tapes #1-5, 1988; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - CPSR Camera A Tapes #6-11, 1988; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - CPSR Camera B Tapes #1-5, 1988; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - DLITE, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Experiments in the Future of Reading, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Flow Menu: Submission Tape, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Geometer Workbench, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Geometer's Workbench: Submission Tape, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - The Ideology of Information: Social Costs of New Technology, 1991; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - iRoom Demos, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Flow Menu: LIIST 2000, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Losing Control, 1989; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - PARC ATM Forum: Severe Tire Damage excerpt, 1995; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - PARC: Interviews from "The PARC Story", 1995; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - PARC: Stories from Startup Land, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - PARC: XFR: The Design Story, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Roger Boisjoly MIT presentation, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - SDI Debate at Stanford Reel 3 of 3, 1986; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Self: The Video, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Sensemaker, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - SGCHI Terry Winograd, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Smithsonian World: From Information to Wisdom?, 1991; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Some Paskian Artefacts, 2001; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Stick it on the Wall, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - The Truesteel Affair, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - US Senate on Virtual Reality, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - A Windowed Perspective Into the History of Networked Computing and Distributed Work Groups, 1991; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - 2000 Reports and Retrospective Part 1 of 2, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - 2000 Reports and Retrospective Part 2 of 2, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Accelerating Innovation, 1990; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Barehands, 2000; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Beyond Words: New Tools for the Learning Community, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Computers in Context, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Design 94: International Design Project Part 1, 1994; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Design 94: International Design Project Part 2, 1994; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Design 95: Public Presentation Part 1, 1995; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Design 95: Public Presentation Part 2, 1995; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Design 95: Project Overviews, 1995; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Effective Lecturing: Classroom Environment, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Effective Lecturing: Actively Engaging Students and Getting Students to Think, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Ethics and Education, 1991; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Living in the Future with Knowledge Navigator, 1989; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Logonet, Inc., 1987; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - New Paradigms for Using Computers, 1995; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Highlights from the conference on "New Paradigms for Using Computers", 1994; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Newton, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - PARC: The Final Demonstration of the Xerox 'Star' Computer Tape 1, 1981; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - PARC: The Final Demonstration of the Xerox 'Star' Computer Tape 2, 1981; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - Selker Sampler, 1991; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - UIST '98 Video Proceedings, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - UIST 2000 Video Proceedings, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - University Workshop 1995 NYU, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - University Workshop 1995 Kyoto, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - University Workshop 1995 Sweden, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - University Workshop 1995 Toronto, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - University Workshop 1995 Italy, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - University Workshop 1995 Stanford, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - University Workshop 1995 Utrecht, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - University Workshop 1995 RCA, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - University Workshop 1996, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - University Workshop, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 11)
  - 80s video, SF TV station, Stanford Students and Staff, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Bringing Design to Software, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - The Business of America… and Update, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - CHI '83: Sketchpad, 1983; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - CHI '88 Technical video Program, 1988; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - CHI '90 Technical Video Program, 1990; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - CHI '94 Video Program, 1994; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - CHI 99 Opening Plenary, 1999; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Computer Professionals and Social Responsibility Part 1, 1988; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - A Conversation on Interaction, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Creating the Virtualities in Which We Live, 1993; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - CS447 Sportscope, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - CS447 B Final Presentations, 1999; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - CSCW '94 Technical Video Program, 1994; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - David Liddle - 147 Talk, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Dr. Douglas C. Engelbart, 2005; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 12)
  - Expert Systems 88 - Grand Finale, 1988; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Guides 3.0, 1990; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - InterChange: Interview with Terry Winograd, 1999; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - INTERCHI '93 Technical Video Program, 1993; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Machines that Think, 1987; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - PARC: DLITE Video for CHI '97, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - PARC: Information Visualizer, 1997; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - PARC: Interaction Design for Ubiquitous Computing, 2000; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Personal Roving Presence, 2001; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - RCA Projects 96, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - SDA Debate at Stanford Reels 1 and 2, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Sensemaker, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - SIGGRAPH 98 Conference Proceedings, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Starfire, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - "Starfire" Directors' Cut, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - Star Wars Research: A University Perspective, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - University Workshop 1997, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - University Workshop 1997 Summary, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 12)
  - 10 Jahre, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 13)
  - CLIHC Keynote, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - CS 247a 99, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Fluid Interaction, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - iRoom demos, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Knowledge Navigator, 1988; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - UIST 2001 Presentation, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - SHRDLU - Terry Winograd, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - SIGGRAPH 99 Conference Proceedings, 1999; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Unlabeled video, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Barehands (1 of 2), 2000; 1 videotape(s) (Mini DV) (Box 13)
  - Barehands (2 of 2), 2000; 1 videotape(s) (Mini DV) (Box 13)
  - Raw iRoom Demo Footage, 2001; 1 videotape(s) (Mini DV) (Box 13)
  - iRoom Final Demos, 2001; 1 videotape(s) (Mini DV) (Box 13)
  - PointRight Final Submit, 2000; 1 videotape(s) (Mini DV) (Box 13)
  - Stephanie, 1 videotape(s) (Mini DV) (Box 13)
  - Unlabeled video, 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV); 1 videotape(s) (Mini DV) (Box 13)
- Subject Files, individual
  - "A" Students (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Agre, Philip E. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "B" Students (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Bella, David A. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Benson, Ian (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bigelow, Chuck (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Bikson, Tora K. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bobrow, Danny (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Borenstien, Nathaniel S. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Brooks, Rodney A. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Brown, John S. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "C" Students (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Carroll, John (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Cashman, Paul M. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Chapman, David (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Ciborra, Claudio U. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Clark, Herbert (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Conklin, Jeff (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Coyne, Richard (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "D" Students (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - De Michelis, G. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - De Koven, Bernard (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dijkstra, Edsger (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dreyfus& Hubert (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "E" Students (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Ehn, Pelle (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Engelbart, D.C. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "F" Students (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fikes, Richard E. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fischer, Gerhard (Box 5)
  - Floyd, Christiane (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Follesdal, Dagfinn (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Friedman, Batya (Box 5)
  - "G" Students (Box 5)
  - Goguen, Joseph A. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Gold, Rich (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Goldhaber, Michael (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Grudin, Jonathan T. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - "H" Students (Box 6)
  - Haraway, Donna (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hartfield, Bradley (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hofstadter, Douglas R. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Holt, Anatol W. (Box 6)
  - "I" Students (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Ishii, Hiroshi (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "J" Students (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "K" Students (Box 6)
  - Kapor, Mitch (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Kay, Alan (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Kling, Rob (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "L" Students (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Lakin, Fred (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lenat, Douglas B. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Levy, David (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Linde, Charlotte (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "M" Students (Box 7)
  - Malone, Thomas W. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - March, James G. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - McCall, Raymond (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - McCarthy, John (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "N" Students (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Nardi, Bonnie (Box 7)
  - Nass, Clifford (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Naur, Peter (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Negroponte, Nicholas (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Nicodemus, Matt (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Nissenbaum, Helen (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Norman, Donald (Box 7)
  - Nygaard, Kristen (1 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Nygaard, Kristen (2 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Nygaard, Kristen (3 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "O" Students (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Orlikowski, Wanda (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "P" Students (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Parnas, David L. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Polanyi, Michael (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "R" Students (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "R" Students (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Roberts, Eric (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Rogers, Yvonne (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Ross, Douglas T. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Rubin, Andee (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Rubin, Andee (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - "S" Students (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Samuelson, Pamela (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Scacchi, Walt (Box 8, Folder 18)